
Speaker 1  (00:02)
I was born in Singapore. I moved when I was 2
I took my first flight when I was 6 months old, maybe 
I moved to Tokyo. Then, Athens. 

Speaker 1  (00:23)
Then, so (Seoul)
Then, Mumbai. Then, back to Singapore for 5 years. Then, a year in the US And I'm now halfway through my second year in Scotland. 

Speaker 1  (00:43)
At saint Andrews. I study Computer Science. But I've been told by many that I don't really study Computer Science. 

Speaker 1  (00:58)
That's also because I'm Somewhat of a recluse, at least 2, the Computer Science department. I transferred from the USA did my first year in Carleton and Minnesota. And as a result I arrived a year late 
And I don't know anybody from my year group 
Or I didn't 
at least I'm getting to know them now. 

Speaker 1  (01:36)
That's not 
Who I am? Is who I am right now? I want to study thought. 

Speaker 1  (01:52)
And that means I want to study reasoning. I want to study logic. I want to study language. 

Speaker 1  (02:02)
And in many ways that 
Are difficult for me. I want to study humans, too. But, and I truly believe this: 

Speaker 1  (02:25)
I am bad. With humans. And in many ways, I do think it is everybody and mine's fault. 

Speaker 1  (02:45)
Because people are lying all the time. But lying to themselves. But just to me, a lot too, but lying to themselves. 

Speaker 1  (03:00)
And lies compound in a system; they're exponential 
Don't you ever think ever should be exponential? 
To the number of layers In a network 
Or to the length of a path? Think of it as a brain is a graph of nodes with edges. 

Speaker 1  (03:32)
A line of thought. A path is just a sequence of nodes connected by edges through that graph. It has a line length 
Crucially, all of its nodes have a degree 
Other edges. 

Speaker 1  (03:56)
This is a one to n transformation. A fork. This makes the graph a tree. 

Speaker 1  (04:07)
But it's a recursive tree. It jumps up. This means in the chain of processing 
While it never goes upwards in physical time It goes backwards. 

Speaker 1  (04:38)
Through recursion. Is recursion just returning to a previous state? There's a recursion, just memory 

Speaker 1  (05:10)
As you might be able to tell, I get distracted easily. I don't know who I'm talking to either. I know who asked the question. 

Speaker 1  (05:26)
But I'm answering to many people at once. 

Speaker 1  (05:42)
My question is 
Can you understand being lied to If you realised I was lying to myself. 
